KYLE RASSWEILER

C Phone: +1-613-724-9141

□ Email: jobs@kylerassweiler.ca

↑ Portfolio: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca Github: www.github.com/rassweiler

(<u>*</u>) Code Camp: <u>https://www.freecodecamp.org/kylerassweiler</u>

Summary

Engineering Specialist with experience in: software development, networking, programmable logic controllers, robotics, electronics, and machining.

I am currently in a React/Node/Electron deep dive, but also have experience with Python and various sql/nosql databases.

Skills	
Software	Angular, Apache2, Assembly(PIC), C++, CMake, Django, Git, Gitlab, Github, HTML, JavaScript, Meteor, Mongoose, Node, PHP, Python, React, Redux
Virtualisation	Virtual Box, Qemu/KVM, Docker
Systems	BSD, Arch, Debian, Windows, Proxmox
Databases	MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresql, SQLite
Hardware	AB(Micro800), Arduino, Mitsubishi, Omron, Raspberry Pi, Toyopuc, Zigbee
	Projects
KRello	A simple Trello clone developed using react and redux with jest and enzyme for testing.
	Site: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/krello/ Demo: https://krello.kylerassweiler.com/
	Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/krello
KR-Display	A responsive Meteor application for the display of SQL data. The system uses jobs to schedule information updates from the SQL server, the jobs then update the local MongoDB database.
	Site: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/kr-display/ Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/kr-display
Kawasaki AS Parser	A Kawasaki robot backup parser written in TypeScript for browser or Node. The library also includes TypeScript interfaces for use in new projects.
	Website: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/kawasaki-parser/ Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/kawasaki-as-parser

Robot Project Utility Mk2

A simple utility written in JS, HTML, CSS, React, and Electron(Node.js). The utility allows the user to view robot backup information from various $\hbox{robot brands} \, \hbox{(Currently Kawasaki), and is also used to compare two backups} \\$ then determine any change points. The utility can also be used for work planning.

Site: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/robot-project-utility/ Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/robot-project-utility

Experience

Engineering Specialist

2017 - Present

TEMA (Toyota)

PLC programming, Robotic Vision (Robeye system), 3D Factory Design, Robot programming, Electrical system troubleshooting, Improving processes and designs, Work planning, Commissioning, Equipment buy offs, Vendor support, Laser Welding, Friction Stir Welding, Aluminium Spot Welding

Robotics Technician

2014 - 2017

FIO Automotive

PLC programming, Robot programming, Machining, Electrical system wiring, Electronics repairing, Robot repairing, Weld condition setup and modification, Setup SCADA system and PLC networking.

Operational Technician Repair equipment, Preventative Maintenance, Inspections.

2012 - 2014

Abbott Point Of Care

Education

Electro-Mechanical Engineering Technician

Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON.

2010 - 2012

Computer Animation

Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON.

2007 - 2010